# Janusz Skonieczny

- Wiślana 32c, 05-092 Łomianki Dolne (Poland)

To whom it may conern

Warsaw, 3rd October 2019

Dear Sir/Madam,

I am looking for a remote Full Stack Python Developer or IT Consultant position, either permanent or B2B on project basis.

I have been working on IT projects for 19 years on various positions. I have 16 years experience in management positions, leading teams of developers and consulting on software solutions, system integrations and IT processes.

I have been working with Microsoft Services on implementing a software platform for a major Polish bank. I have also been working on many other projects, deploying a mature Identity Management processes and integration for financial and telecom institutions.

I like working with the latest cutting edge technology and thus have been working with different vendors and technologies, from Java, through .NET to Python. I also keep tabs on what is what in SaaS offerings.

Everywhere I work, I try to implement processes that increase reliability, automation and accountability. I believe it is a foundation for great quality in any IT related project and leads to achieving goals quickly. Repeating great performance in each new iteration without being bogged down by regression is key in agile development. I've been consulting for a 1200 employee software vendor to improve their software development process.

Recently I helped to build a recruitment platform with over 15 milion profiles of IT specialist. Prior to that I built a SaaS grade book for Polish schools which I sold as a finished product to a publishing house.

My calling rate is 30\$ per hour or 5000\$ monthly. I am happy to take on a trial project to showcase my skills and product quality.

In attachment you will find my full resume. Please check out my LinkedIn profile and recommendations.

Yours sincerely,

Janusz Skonieczny

# PERSONAL INFORMATION Janusz Skonieczny

- Wiślana 32c, 05-092 Łomianki Dolne (Poland)
- +48 578 271 924
- ✓ Janusz.Skonieczny+CV@BraveLabs.pl
- http://www.Skonieczny.pl in https://www.linkedin.com/in/skonieczny/ https://github.com/wooyek https://stackoverflow.com/users/260480/janusz-skonieczny
- Skype janusz.skonieczny

# PREFERRED JOB

# Full Stack Python Developer / IT Consultant

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Jan 2014 Full

# Full Stack Python Developer / IT Consultant

**Brave Labs** 

IT Consulting, Training, Audit, Software Development process design and bespoke software development.

#### Feb 2010-Dec 2013

## **CEO**

Brave Labs sp. z o.o.

Primarily focused on development of SaaS internet gradebook for elementary, middle and high schools — www.Dziennik.edu.pl.

Our goal was to create a simple, high quality and affordable solution for schools, so they can use upto-date information, techniques and technology to create the best possible learning environment.

Managing a start-up company with secondary focus on consulting, auditing and developments services, mainly around cloud and web development.

## Jul 2006-Jan 2010

# CTO

Qualent Software Sp. z o.o.

Managing all operations in services and software production department with main focus on project management and production process reliability. Supporting CEO in sales and marketing activities.

# Apr 2005-May 2006

## **CTO**

Internetium Sp. z o.o.

Owner of the production process, responsible for it's compliance with QMS for ISO 9000:2000 certification. Deployment of technologies and procedures to improve quality of services.

Responsible for company team of developers, their technology proficiency and training directions.

Projects management, indirectly responsible for all company projects. Analyze business requirements and prepare project specification. Leading software projects in Microsoft technologies (.NET, ASP.NET, ActiveDirectory, MIIS2003, WebServices, COM+, MSSQL200).

Business or sector Information and communication

# Aug 2003-Apr 2005

# Project manager

Internetium sp. z o.o.

Projects management. Analyze business requirements and prepare project specification. Leading



Curriculum vitae

Janusz Skonieczny

software projects in Microsoft technologies (ADO.NET, ASP.NET, ActiveDirectory, MIIS2003, WebServices, COM+, MSSQL200).

Business or sector Information and communication

Aug 2002–Jul 2003 Team Lead

JAVART Sp. z o.o.

J2EE & J2SE project managment and development.

Business or sector Information and communication

Oct 2001–Jul 2002 Software designer/programmer

JAVART Sp. z o.o.

JAVA (J2EE) programmer and designer mainly Web applications written for a comunications

company.

Business or sector Information and communication

Jun 2000–Nov 2001 Customer service consultant

Compaq

Deployment of Direct Banking software for customers of Citibank and Bank Handlowy.

Business or sector Financial and insurance activities

Jan 1998–Apr 1998 IT Service Support

**Tulip Computers** 

Student part time job in IT support department.

Business or sector Information and communication

Jun 1997–Jun 1997 Student Practice - (Glenrothes, Fife, Scotland)

Hughes Microelectronics Europa Ltd.

GUI Blakell programming.

Development of data-logging code and documentation for construction tests of electronic devices on

production line.

Business or sector Professional, scientific and technical activities

Sep 1996–May 1997 Cleaning Service

Fife Council Domestic Services
Part time job during colleage studies.

Business or sector Other service activities

**EDUCATION AND TRAINING** 

Oct 2001–Oct 2003 Computer Science, Computer networks & Systems

Politechnika Warszawska

Oct 1997–Sep 2001 Computer Science, Computer systems & networks

Politechnika Warszawska

Sep 1996–Jun 1997 Electronic and Electrical Engineering

HND

msc



Fife College of Further and Higher Education

# 1993–1996 Digital Electronics

Technik Elektronik

Engineering High school (Technikum elektroniczne gen. Zajączka)

Sep 1985–Jul 1993

euro*pass* 

Wladyslawa Orkana

PERSONAL SKILLS

Mother tongue(s)

Polish

#### Foreign language(s)

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
C2	C2	C2	C2	C2
A1	A1	A1	A1	A1

English German

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user - B1 and B2: Independent user - C1 and C2: Proficient user Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

#### Communication skills

I have good communications skills and experience gained while leading development teams, sales of my company services and roles such as NGO board member and council member for my home town. I try to take advantage of non violent communication and conflict resolution skills.

I have experience with many project management, communication and collaboration related tools, notable examples are: JIRA, Asana, Slack, Basecamp, Trello, GSuite Documents.

As an analyst I have gained very good knowledge of MS Word document setup. I like to have interconnectivity and auto updating reference fields throughout my documents. Locked styling protects consistent look.

## Organisational / managerial skills

I have been a founding partner in Qualent Software and a CTO and shareholder in Internetium startups, where I have coached and shaped 10 person development team.

### Job-related skills

Python, Django, Flask, PyTest, Selenium, SASS, Bootstrap, Heroku, Docker, Dokku, GIT, Linux server admin, HTML5, jQuery, JavaScript, EmberJS

# Digital skills

Information processing	Communication	Content creation	Safety	Problem- solving
Proficient user	Proficient user	Proficient user	Proficient user	Proficient user

Digital skills - Self-assessment grid

# Other skills

Software Development, Agile Methodologies, .NET, Requirements Analysis, Project Management, Architecture, SQL, Scrum, Cloud Computing, Google App Engine, CSS, Visual Studio, ISO 9001, Cruise Control .NET, C#, Usability Testing, User Interface Design, User Experience Design, Software Quality Assurance, Quality Auditing, Product Development, Software Development Process Design, Designs, Software Development Life Cycle, Microsoft SQL Server, Database Design, Web Applications, Software Engineering, ASP.NET, Software Design, Web Development, Software Project Management, Databases, Integration, Web Services, Testing, Mobile Devices, Subversion, Design Patterns, Architectures, Test Driven Development, ADO.NET, SEO, SEM, Google Apps



#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

#### Certifications

Microsoft Certified Solution Developer
Microsoft Certified Application Developer
Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist SQL Server 2005
Microsoft Certified Database Administrator Microsoft SQL Server 2000

TS: Microsoft® SQL Server™ 2005 - Implementation and Maintenance

Managing and Maintaining a Microsoft Windows Server 2003 Environment

Planning, Implementing, and Maintaining a Microsoft Windows Server 2003 Active Directory Infrastructure

Installing, Configuring, and Administering Microsoft® SQL Server™ 2000 Enterprise Edition

Analyzing Requirements and Defining Microsoft .NET Solution Architectures

Developing and Implementing Web Applications with Visual C#™ .NET

Developing XML Web Services and Server Components with Microsoft Visual C# .NET and the Microsoft .NET Framework

Developing and Implementing Windows®-based Applications with C#™ .NET

Designing and Implementing Databases with Microsoft® SQL Server™ 2000 Enterprise Edition

# NGO voluntary work

I am a passionate NGO supporter and I help my local community through organization of various social events, like yearly bazaar of used toys for kids, local tourism, bird watching, neighborly DIY and sharing achievements hobby and art projects.

I also help to improve local government oversight by spreading knowledge about watchdog operations and the right to public information by citizens.

I am a consultant for NGOs within the Sector-3.0 project ran by Polish American Freedom Foundation (PAFW) and Fundacja Rozwoju Społeczeństwa Informacyjnego (FRSI). I help NGOs fulfill technology related needs but also help in law aspects of running an NGO.

# Programming trainer for teachers

On a country level I help to spread programming skills through projects training teachers in the use of modern programming languages, robotics and skills related to programming but not necessarily used through computers.

I also advocate for use of professionally required tools that are easy to integrate in school projects but are often ignored by the lack of interest in what employers now really require.

I helped to create a Python 101 course for Koduj z Klasą. I am a trainer in Misja Programowanie.

### **Charter School**

I am a board member of my kids charter school. I help to push our teachers into innovative ways to teach and implement newest knowledge about successful education in day to day work.

We want to create a school environment that will help students to fulfill their potential. We change schooling from one-way knowledge passing activities to an environment where students learn to constantly acquire knowledge themselves and teachers are there to steer and help along the way.